A Guide to the William J. Norfleet Papers, 1934-1955
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
William J. Norfleet Papers, 1934-1955
Library of Virginia
26217
1.8 cubic feet
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Mrs. William J. Norfleet, 15 January 1965.
Biographical/Historical Information
William James Norfleet was born in Amelia County, Virginia on 20 October 1885. He was the son of William Chamberlayne Norfleet and Florence Flournoy. He married Carrie Knoll Mason (b. 1887) on 16 November 1920. They had two daughters. William J. Norfleet was employed as an accountant and auditor with the Interstate Commerce Commission from 1917 to 1935, and was Chief Accountant with the Federal Communications Commission from 1935 until his retirement in 1955.
Scope and Content Information
Papers, 19334-1955, of William J. Norfleet (b. 1885) of Bethesda, Maryland. Includes research files on Amelia County, research files on railroads, and personal files.
Series I, Amelia County Research Files, include information on a variety of topics related to the county's history and its people. They contain abstracts relating to Amelia County from the Acts of Assembly, Calendar of Virginia State Papers, Journals of the House of Burgesses and House of Delegates, legislative petitions, various order books, and newspapers. Also included is information on the county's churches, various families, notable individuals, landmarks, post roads and mail service, Revolutionary and Confederate soldiers, county formation and boundaries and other topics. Of particular note in this series is information on Lewis E. Harvie (1809-1887) written by his son Edwin J. Harvie (1835-1911), genealogical notes on the Norfleet family compiled by Matilda Augusta Norfleet, and Bible records of the Burfoot and Tucker families.
Series II, Railroad Research Files, contain clippings, correspondence, information on early railroads in the United States and Virginia, and files relating to specific railroad companies. There is a substantial amount of information concerning the Winchester and Potomac Railroad.
Series III, Personal Files, include clippings, correspondence, personnel files, a few photographs, and miscellaneous material. Much of the information in this series relates to Norfleet's service with the Federal Communications Commission.
Organization
Series I. Amelia County Research Files. Series II. Railroad Research Files. Series III. Personal Files.
Contents List
- Amelia County Research Files
  The Amelia County Research Files include information on a variety of topics related to the county's history and its people. They contain abstracts relating to Amelia County from the Acts of Assembly, Calendar of Virginia State Papers, Journals of the House of Burgesses and House of Delegates, legislative petitions, various order books, and newspapers. Also included is information on the county's churches, various families, notable individuals, landmarks, post roads and mail service, Revolutionary and Confederate soldiers, county formation and boundaries and other topics. Of particular note in this series is information on Lewis E. Harvie (1809-1887) written by his son Edwin J. Harvie (1835-1911), genealogical notes on the Norfleet family compiled by Matilda Augusta Norfleet, and Bible records of the Burfoot and Tucker families.
  - Acts of Assembly and Council Journals (Abstracts) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Amelia County Order Book 1, 1735-1746 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Amelia County Order Book 2, 1746-1751 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Amelia County Order Books (Abstracts) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Amelia County Wills and Administrations, 1735-1800 (Index) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Birds (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Bott, William (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Briggs, George R. - Recollections of Civil War Service (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Burk, John Daly (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Calendar of Virginia State Papers (Abstracts) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Census of Pensioners, 1840 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Christ Church Sunday School - Memories by Mary Southall Hardaway (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Churches (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Churches - Baptist (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Churches - Dutch Reformed (Mattoax) (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Churches - Episcopal (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Churches - Methodist (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Churches - Presbyterian (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Clerks (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Clippings (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Confederate Soldiers of Amelia County (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Council Members, Burgesses, Delegates, Senators (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - County Formation and Boundaries (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Dawson, Musgrave (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Entertainments - Reconstruction Period (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Evans, Moses Ford Thomas (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Families of Amelia County
    - Archer (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Berkeley (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Bibb (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Bolling - "Bollingbrooke" (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Booker (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Brunskill (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Burfoot Family Bible Records (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Chappell (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Clement (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Cobbs (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Cocke (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Cooke (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Eggleston (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Finney (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Flournoy (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Flournoy-Poindexter Parke Genealogical Chart (Filed in Genealogical Charts) (Box n/a/)
    - Giles (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Gregory (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Grigg (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Harrison (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Harvie (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Harvie, Edwin James, "Life and Times of Lewis E. Harvie, 1895 (2 copies) (Box 2, Folder 3-6)
    - Hundley (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Jeter (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Jones (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Mason (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Meaux (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Mumford/Munford (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Nash (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Norfleet (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - "Norfleet Clan" compiled by Matilda Augusta Norfleet, 1936-1937 (2 copies) (Box 2, Folder 15-16)
    - Pride (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Robertson (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Southall (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Southall Family Military Records (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Tabb (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Terhune (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Truehart (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Tucker Family Bibles (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Walker (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Walton (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Willson/Wilson (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Miscellaneous Notes on Amelia Families (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Fanning, David (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Finney Deed, 1747 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Giles Bridge (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - "Glenmore" (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Hanks, Nancy (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Historical Markers (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Horses (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Indians (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Journals of the House of Burgesses (Abstracts) (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Journal of the House of Delegates, 7 December 1808 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Justices (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Land Marks (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Land Patents and Grants (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Legislative Petitions (Abstracts) (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Lost "Clergy List" of 1758 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Maps (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Mills (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Mines and Minerals (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Miscellaneous Notes (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Money (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - "Morven" (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Moton, Robert Russa (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Newspaper Abstracts, 1800-1836 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Notebooks (3) Containing Notes on Amelia County History (Box n/a)
  - Obituaries in Richmond Newspapers, 1804-1838 (Index) (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Pay Rolls of Militia Entitled to Land Bounty (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Pioneers (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Pleasants, James (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Post Roads and Mail Service (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Proctor, William (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Railroads (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Revolutionary War Data from McAllister's Virginia Militia (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Robertson, Beverly Holcombe (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Ruffin, Edmund (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Schools (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Soldiers of Amelia County (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Thomson, John (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Thompson, Wiley (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Tombstone Inscriptions (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Walker, John William (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Walker, Leroy Pope (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - War Between the States (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Railroad Research Files
  The Railroad Research Files contain clippings, correspondence, information on early railroads in the United States and Virginia, and files relating to specific railroad companies. There is a substantial amount of information concerning the Winchester and Potomac Railroad.
  - Clippings (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence re: Inquiries and Research Materials, 1934-1935 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Early Railroads in the United States (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Early Railroads in Virginia (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Specific Railroads
    - Amelia Railroad Company (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Atlantic Coast Line Railroad Company (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Baltimore and Ohio Railroad Company (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Baltimore and Potomac Railroad Company (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Chesapeake and Ohio Company (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Chesterfield Railroad Company (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - City Point Railroad Company (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Erie and Kalamazoo Railroad (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Experimental Railway (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Falling Creek Railway (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Georgia Railroad and Banking Company (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Greenville and Roanoke Railroad Company (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Lynchburg and New River Railroad Company (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - New Castle and Frenchtown Turnpike and Railroad Company (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Norfolk and Western Railway Company (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Petersburg Railroad Company (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Richmond and Danville Railroad Company (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Richmond and Petersburg Railroad (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Richmond, Fredericksburg & Potomac Railroad Company (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Seaboard Air Line Railroad Company (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Staunton and Potomac Railroad (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Southern Railway Company (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Valley Railroad (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Winchester and Potomac Railroad Company (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Winchester and Strausburg Railroad Company (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Personal Files
  The Personal Files include clippings, correspondence, personnel files, a few photographs, and miscellaneous material. Much of the information in this series relates to Norfleet's service with the Federal Communications Commission.
  - Clippings (Box 4, Folder 30-31)
  - Correspondence (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Personnel (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Photographs (Box 4, Folder 35)